Come and to the complete data structure and algorithms, of course, we are asked an exercise number
63 to write a function that reverse a link, at least a W link, at least.
So consider this is that the injured list that contains three nodes.
This is the start.
I says no, it contains no one.
This is the second node.
Contains two and.
The third note that contains three this we refer to NULL.
And this we refer to now, of course, and this will return next and the previous two and three.
These are the notes game.
The pointer of the head, here is the head.
Have you?
This is a normal link, at least our mission, and this exercise is to make and reverse this link,
at least into a reverse link, at least such that we start from the head from the last position.
So the head were recorded.
At least not as the head.
And also, it were none that were referred to.
And this we refer also to the first one that we have reversed and OK, our mission is to reverse this
doubly linked list.
So how to do that, how to make reverse function?
I am waiting your solution.
You can go to the lectures and see how to make it how the concept behind it came.
So reverse first list.
OK.
So please get guys referred for us and make a favor for us by mandating us five stars on Udemy because
you will support us making and add new exercise and add the new lecture every week.
OK, so first of all, creating the notes
or creating attempt?
No.
--, it's equal.
It's equal to now.
Then note grant equals to had.
First or the second step is where the next and previous of all for all nodes of doubly linked list,
while good and does not equal to none, then them but equal to pure and the great guys like these questions
that trick behind them is the link.
So if we know how to do to which then links how to alike and deal with the links we need.
To make a while value because we are going through all the notes to change the previous and the next
previous and the next for all the notes.
By the way, we have created a term and the current notes.
So this current and temped notes will act as a like intermediate containers, intermediate notes that
will switch and the swap the next and the previous notes for all the notes of the double anchored list
by making current that grid equal to.
And remember, while while dealing with the link, at least you are dealing with a two Pinter's, the
Priv, the previous and the next.
OK.
So you should take care about the previous and the next current DOT next equal to TAM and current equal
to good in the breath.
OK.
It's very simple how we swap with.
The next enterprise and this is the the heart of our program, our.
Method the reverse function.
The third step before changing had changed.
This is the changing pattern before changing had to check for the case if empty list and list with only
one note.
OK, so if STEM does not equal to null,
have equal to tamp dot the previous.
OK, we are checking for that case.
If empty list changing had.
Check for empty list or one list.
OK.
This is the check.
Now let's run and see.
Let me reverse this is.
The function this is the list nine, nine, nine, two and four.
This is their normal list.
Let's.
Reverse it before we printed it becomes four, two and nine nine.
And while printing the list, the reverse is the reverse of the reverse is the normal.
So nine, nine, nine, two and four.
OK, so we have reversed our our list correctly and we have created this function in the correct way.
Using this while loop that the swab.